Mo Zhai

150 E Schiller Street Apt 505 Elmhurst IL 60126

E-mail: mozhai@live.com Phone: (773)678-3620

Me

I am an experienced software engineer with over 4 years of professional experience. My experience covers development using Objective C, Java, .NET, C++, Javascript, and many other languages on top of most popular frameworks. I have delivered several mobile apps in iOS and Android App Stores as well as enterprise web applications. I am a hard worker with great leaning skills, and I have an enthusiastic heart for IT industry.

Education DePaul University

Graduation March, 2012

Master of Science in **Computer Game Development**, Graduate School of College of Computing and Digital Media GPA=3.98

Tianjin Normal University

Graduation July, 2007

Bachelor's degree in **Computer Engineering**, emphasis on Information Engineering GPA=3.21 First rank scholarship

Experience

Software Engineer @ Echelon Consulting, L.L.C.

5/2012 - now

- iOS and Android development for app stores, using Objective C, and Java
- Mobile app backed-end development using C#, Lucene.net and Python
- Business web application development using Liferay, Java, Dojo, and .Net

Software developer internships@ Space to Play

2/2012 - 4/2012

• Creating a 3Ds Max plug-in in C++, which facilitates editing and visualization of urban 3D building models from geo-spatial database (PostGIS).

Graduate Assistant and Tech support @ CDM, DePaul University

01/2011 - 03/2012

 Daily Maintaining and management for labs of the College CDM. Prepare software and equipments for professors.

Network engineer @ China TieTong- Equipment Center

08/2007 - 03/2009

- Analyzing, and refining the central node of the whole company PSTN network.
- Tools and scripts development for internal use

Skills

- Frameworks: iOS, Android, Liferay, ASP.Net, J2EE, Dojo, Lucene.Net, OpenGL
- Language: Objective C, Java, JavaScript, C++, C#, Python
- IDE: Visual Studio, Xcode, Eclipse, and etc.
- Platforms: MacOS X, Windows, Linux

Project List

SIDLEY mobile for iOS

Capacity: Objective C, Cocoa touch, Core Data

Responsibility: Took part in development Sidley marketing app for iOS5/6, and in charge of development brand new iOS7/8 app with flat-design. The app supports both iPhone and iPad, and it is optimized for iPhone 6/6plus by using auto-layout storyboard. In the app, dynamic contents are synced from proxy server and persisted in Core Data. Uls render the updated data to represent users news, bio info, and location interests. This app also supports topics and people searching. **App store link:** https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sidley-mobile/id574510600

Project List

SIDLEY mobile apps backend

Capacity: Asp.Net, Lucene.net, Python

Responsibility: In charge of development of the searching APIs for SIDLY mobile. A standalone C# and Python application firstly pre-processes target documents, and then it uses Lucene.net to create full-text index of processed data. The .Net proxy server finally uses this index to dynamically create ranked topic list by comparing the similarities between grouped documents and input string.

In charge of development of the location APIs for mobile app. The .Net based proxy server caches dynamic nearby location info every few hours by querying Google Place API with given criteria.

Then the server uses caches location data to fulfill mobile app requests in JSON. In charge of development push-notification service in C# for Android GCM.

Took part in the development of the documents sync service on top of SQL Server database. CRUD operations on management pages lead to contents sync and notification push in mobile app.

SIDLEY mobile for Android

Capacity: Java, Android UI, SQLite

Responsibility: In charge of development Sidley marketing android app from scratch to Play store. including testing, and deployment. The app is targeted from android 2.2. to 4.2, and it is based on fragment/activity UIs for both phone and tablet. Dynamic contents are synced from proxy server and persisted in local SQLite database. A new created ePub reader renders document based contents and a customized webView displays bio info of people in Sidley.

Play store link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sidley.sidleymobile.android

Atkearney.com Portal web site 6.2

Capacity: Java, Javascript, Dojo, Liferay, Python, CSS, Responsive Design

Responsibility: Took part in the portal migrations from Liferay 6.1 to 6.2. Created javascript widgets to replace old Jsp contents. Developed and updated portlets and hooks for customized web Uls and functionalities. Created a distributable similarity comparing tools in python and writing Beanshell scrips to support auto translation for more than 20 different country sites. Also working on portal theme updating to apply responsive design.

Link: http://www.atkearney.com/

SIDLEY Doc Enterprise iOS App for Good Dynamic

Capacity: Objective C, C#, Good security (https://www1.good.com/secure-mobility-solution/)
Responsibility: Developed an highly secured mobile app for sensitive documents using Good SDK.
In charge of data persistence migration from unsafe PList to encrypted Good CoreData in mobile app. Took part in the development of the file explorer like UI with CRUD and searching supported.
In charge of app updating from iOS SDK5 to 8 as long as Good SDK updating from 1.2 to 1.10.

Staffing availabilities Intranet project

Capacity: Javascript, dGrid, Dojo, JSP, LIferay

Responsibility: In charge of the development for a one-page web Intranet application to visualize staffing availabilities data. The web application sends async request to get data from backend server and saves the data to dStore. An Excel styled grid smoothly renders availabilities data in cells with column locking and scrolling. This web application also supports sorting, filleting and Excel exporting with multi-select dropdown widgets.

A.T. Kearney: Ideas and Insights for iOS

Capacity: Objective C, Cocoa touch, LinkedIn API, PushSharp

Responsibility: In charge of flat-design UI reimplementation, YouTube video playback, backend notification server updating, and social network integration. In the app, users can read or watch latest insights contents and post their opinions to Goole Plus, LinkedIn, Facebook, and twitter. **App store link**: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/a.t.-kearney-ideas-insights/id506749703

A.T. Kearney IMO Intranet project (Current Project)

Capacity: Asp.net MVC, Javascript, Razor

Responsibility: Developing a financial web applications for merging cases using ASP.net MVC framework. In charge of setting up the app infrastructure including sql server database connections, entity framework, and javascript libraries. Implementing the web application layout, functionality and UIs of each web page for the business logic.